Guide to the Humphreys-Marvin-Olmstead Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- GEORGE WILLIAM ERVING PAPERS, 1803-1808; Series II; 1" (1/5 box)
  - Diplomatic Miscellany
    - Gazeta de Madrid del Viernes 8 de Enero 1808 18 Jan 1808], Num. 3, endorsed [by George W. Erving?]: "The French and Spanish blockade decree of Decr 1807", 1808 January 8 (Box 5, Folder 174)
- MARVIN FAMILY PAPERS, 1794-1864; Series III; 3" (3/5 box)
  This series contains papers of members of the Marvin family and of the Colt and Ely families with whom they were allied by marriage (see the family chart at the beginning of the register for details). The series is divided into five sections, of which the largest by far is Family Correspondence. The letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Contained here are mostly unconnected letters, although the correspondence of Elizabeth Marvin (Box 5, folders 186-187) does form a cohesive group concerning the death of her husband, Judah Colt. Bereavement and the consolations of religion are, in fact, frequent topics in this section, whose contents deal with family news and financial affairs. Only one letter diverges, that of Theophilus Marvin (Box 5, folder 193), which gives an account of a lecture about a visit to a Waldensian community in northern Italy.
  The remaining papers in Series III consist of a collection of Marvin family financial papers, twelve land patents, and genealogical notes about the Marvin, Colt, and other families. Pertaining to the Ely family are financial papers of Elizabeth Colt Ely (Box 5, folder 198), and a brigade order addressed to Seth Ely (Box 5, folder 197).
  - Family Correspondence
    - Astley, Thomas
      See: box 5, folder 187
    - Billington, Miss_______
    - Colt, Elizabeth (Marvin)
      See: box 5, folder 186
    - Colt, [Joseph] S., b. 1766
      - ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1832 October 17 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Colt, Judah, 1761-1832
      - ALS to Seth Ely, 1764-1847, 1808 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 176)
      - 2 ALS to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1797 May 24, 1800 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Colt, Judah (1761-1832), and Ely, E[lizabeth?] C[olt (1802-1835?]
      - 2 ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1829 August 10, September 16 (Box 5, Folder 177)
        See also: box 5, folder 180
      - Colt, Mrs. Judah
    - Colt, Samuel, b. 1771
      - 2 ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1832 October 22, December 3 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Ely, Ebenezer, of Rochester, N.Y., f1. 1856
      - ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1832 December 6 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - [Ely, Elizabeth Colt, 1802-1835?]
      - ALS to Abigail Deborah Ely [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, 1851 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 180)
        See also: box 5, folder 177
    - Ely, Mary E[lizabeth Marvin, 1826-1866?]
      - ALS to Abigail D[eborah] Ely [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, with a postscript by Sarah [Marvin, 1820-1843?], dated [1836] Dec 8, 1836 December 3-8 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Ely, Seth, 1764-1847
      - ALS to Judah Colt, 1761-1832, 1828 July 8 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Gibson, Elizabeth
    - Gibson, Louisa
    - Hart, Rev. E.
    - Hills, Elizabeth Colt (Ely)
      See: box 5, folder 180
    - Hills, Mrs. Rufus
    - McCall, Mrs. Sarah
    - Marvin, Deborah S[elden, 1779-1802?]
      - ALS to Phoebe Marvin [Mrs. Seth Ely], 1772-1852, undated (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Marvin, Dudley, 1786-1852
      - ALS to Abigail Deborah Ely [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, 1849 September 28 (Box 5, Folder 184)
      - ALS to Seth Ely, 1764-1847, 1826 May 7 (Box 5, Folder 184)
      - ALS to Elihu Marvin, 1791-1878, 1809 September 21 (Box 5, Folder 184)
      - ALS to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1809 December 31 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Marvin, Mrs. Elisha (1742-1817)
      See: box 5, folder 194
    - Marvin, Elisha, 1768-1829
      - ALS to Deacon Elisha Marvin, 1742-1817, and Elizabeth Selden [Mrs. Elisha (1742-1817) Marvin], 1747-1825, [pre-1809?] (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Marvin, Elizabeth, 1767-1834
      - File copy of letter to [Thomas?] Astley, [1832 Oct?] (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - File copy of letter to Miss_______; Billington, 1832 November 2 (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - File copy of letter to [Mrs. Sarah] McCall and Elizabeth and Louisa Gibson, 1832 November 6 [i.e., 7] (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - 2 ALS to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1796 August 28, 1797 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - ALS from [Thomas?] Astley, [1832 October 22] (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - ALS from Miss_______ Billington, 1832 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - ALS from Rev. E_______ Hart, 1832 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - ALS from Mrs. Sarah McCall and Elizabeth and Louisa Gibson, 1832 December 10 (Box 5, Folder 187)
      - ALS from George Poe[?], Jr., 1832 November 2 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Marvin, Elizabeth (Selden)
    - Marvin, Emily (Emila), 1789-1856
      - AL to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1809 June (Box 5, Folder 188)
      - 2 ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, [1828] October 2, 1829 January 2 (Box 5, Folder 188)
        See also: box 5, folder 191
    - Marvin, Enoch, 1774-1840
      - ALS to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1798 April 1 (Box 5, Folder 189)
      - ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1832 November 10 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - M[arvin?], P[enelope?] J[arvis? 1785-1833
      - ALS to Mary Marvin, 1784-1841, 1812 August 25 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Marvin, Sarah, 1820-1843
      See: box 5, folder 181
    - Marvin, Selden (b. 1819), and Marvin, Emily (Emila), 1789-1856
      - ALS to Abigail D[eborah] Ely [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, [pre-1836?] April 6 (Box 5, Folder 191)
        See also: box 5, folder 188
    - Marvin, Susan H., 1816-Aug 1834
      - ALS to Abigail D[eborah] Ely, [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, 1834 April 8 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Marvin, Theophilus R[ogers], 1796-1882
      - ALS to Elizabeth Marvin [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834, 1825 March 7 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Poe, George, Jr.
    - [Selden, Elizabeth?), 1747-1825
      - AL to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1794 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 194)
      - ALS to Elisha Marvin, 1768-1829, 1795 April 9 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Financial Papers
    - Marvin, Deacon Elisha, 1742-1817, estate of: inventories, receipts, memoranda, 1817-1830, undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Miscellaneous deeds, titles, receipts, 1814-1830 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Ely Family Mss
    - Copy of Brigade Order, 3rd Brigade, Connecticut Militia; with Regimental Orders, 33rd Regiment, addressed to: "Seth Ely Junr. Capt. Matross Compy. 33d. Regt.", 1798 August 28, September 7 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Ely, Elizabeth Colt [Mrs. Rufus Hills], 1802-1835: miscellaneous financial papers re estate of:
      - Statement of account with J[ohn?] C[ard?] Selden, b. 1825, Circa 1860 (Box 5, Folder 198)
      - Statement of account of Abigail Deborah Ely [Mrs. Henry M. Gregory], 1813-1879, with J[ohn?] C[ard?] Selden, Circa 1860 (Box 5, Folder 198)
      - Memorandum entitled "Statement of Notes on Hand.", [1860 March 10?] (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Land Patents
    - Colt, Judah, 1767-1832
      - 3 land patents for designated lots of property in Erie County, Pennsylvania, issued by the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to Judah Colt, his heirs and assigns, 1816 June 22, 1827 November 15, 1828 July 1 (Box 4a)
    - Marvin, Enoch, 1774-1840
      - 3 land patents for designated lots of property in Erie County, Pennsylvania, issued by the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to Enoch Marvin, his heirs and assigns, 1836 March 19, May 20 (Box 4a)
      - 5 land patents for designated lots of property in the Town of Erie, Erie County, Pennsylvania, issued by the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to Enoch Marvin, his heirs and assigns, 1836 May 20 (Box 4a)
    - Marvin, E[lihu, 1791-1878?]
      - Land patent for a designated lot of property in Erie County, Pennsylvania, issued by the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to E. Marvin, his heirs and assigns, 1864 October 31 (Box 4a)
  - Genealogy
    - Marvin, Elizabeth [Mrs. Judah Colt], 1767-1834
      - "Extracts from my Journal", 1802-1806 (Box 5, Folder 199)
      - "Family Record of Joseph [1727-1787] Colt's Family", 1831 May (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Families of Humphreys, Marvin, Olmsted, Griswold, Nott, and Selden: genealogical notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 200)
- LEMUEL GREGORY OLMSTED PAPERS, 1830-(1855-1867); Series IV; 7" (1 2/5 boxes)
  Series IV is made up of papers of Lemuel Gregory Olmsted (1808-1880), minister and natural historian. The correspondence in the series is divided into three sections, each arranged alphabetically by author: Personal Correspondence, Third-Party Correspondence, and Family Correspondence. Personal Correspondence contains Olmsted's own correspondence. Incoming letters from family and friends covers such topics as family events and genealogies and research about Joel Barlow, as well as business matters stemming from Olmsted's service as a chaplain in the Union Army. Included in the correspondence are short notes from Henry Ward Beecher, Horace Greeley, and William H. Seward, and a sequence of over sixty letters from Olmsted's daughter, Sarah Lucy, describing her life in Erie, Pennsylvania, from 1860 to 1865. Only five letters written by Olmsted are preserved here; three deal with a job at the Erie Academy. Third-Party Correspondence contains eight letters from persons other than family members. Employment and other business matters are the primary issues discussed. Family Correspondence contains seven letters dealing with family news.
  Aside from correspondence, Series IV contains a number of receipts and other miscellaneous items such as tickets, advertisements, printed matter, diplomas, and genealogical notes. Two items of particular interest are a family photograph and autograph album belonging to Sarah Lucy Olmsted and a journal kept by Lemuel Gregory Olmsted of his travels around New York State during 1830. As well as detailing his social activities and modes of travel, he describes the geological formations and flora and fauna of places he visited, and meditates on philosophical and religious questions.
  - Personal Correspondence
    - Incoming
      - Adams, Oscar, 1865 September 26 (Box 5, Folder 201)
      - Barlow, J H, 1860 July 19 (Box 5, Folder 202)
      - Barlow, Samuel B., 1862 September 18 (Box 5, Folder 202)
      - Barlow, Samuel L. M., 1826-1889, 1860 August 24, 1861 October 1 (Box 5, Folder 202)
      - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887, 1864 April 11 (Box 5, Folder 203)
      - Benedict, Ephraim, b. 1785, 1861 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 203)
      - Blackburn, Rev. M W, 1861 February 12 (Box 5, Folder 204)
      - Blodgett, Gains Mills, 1862 October 23 November 18 (Box 5, Folder 204)
      - Brown, Rev. W Y, undated (Box 5, Folder 204)
      - Caffry, George W.[?], [1858 June 15] (Box 5, Folder 205)
      - Canfield, Christopher R, 1862 November 7 (Box 5, Folder 205)
      - Cary, Phoebe, 1824-1871, [post-1856 August 22] (Box 5, Folder 205)
      - Cochran, C B, [1858?] May 27 (Box 5, Folder 206)
      - Colt, Samuel, 1814-1862, 1861 January 11[?] (Box 5, Folder 206)
      - Cruger, Lewis, 1855 March 30, April 4 (Box 5, Folder 206)
      - Dempsey, James, 1862 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 207)
      - Derickson, D V, 1862 October 30 (Box 5, Folder 207)
      - Dick, John, 1794-1872, 1858 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 208)
      - [Dinsmoor, Sarah Wilson, b. 1824?], 1865 October 19, November 26, 1866 February 14, undated (Box 5, Folder 208)
      - Dwight, Timothy, b. 1811, 1865 December 26 (Box 5, Folder 208)
        See: box 6, folder 226
      - Dwight, Mrs. Timothy (b. 1811)
      - Eagle, Joseph B., 1862 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 209)
      - Eaton, Rev. S J M, 1862 November 7 (Box 5, Folder 209)
      - Ely, Abigail Deborah, 1813-1879, 1863 January 3, 1865 December 12 (Box 5, Folder 210)
      - Ely, Abigail G(regory)
        See: box 6, folder 261
      - Ely, Mrs. Abner Lord
      - Flint, James, 1862 September 23 (Box 5, Folder 211)
      - Goodwin, R J, 1863 March 25 (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872, 1856 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Gregory, Elizabeth B., 1860 February 11 (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Gregory, Mrs. Henry M.
      - Griswold, Mrs. Matthew (1833-1919)
        See: box 6, folder 228-233
      - Hansen, Rev. Isaiah L., 1862 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 213)
      - Hog, A F, 1862 June (Box 5, Folder 213)
      - Humphreys, Anna, 1781-1875, 1862 February 1, 1865 October 18, undated (Box 5, Folder 214)
      - Jackson, Samuel, 1862 November 24 (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - James, G W, 1862 September 24 (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - Jarvis, William, 1858 January 8 (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - Johnson, John O., 1862 August 29, 1865 November 18 (Box 5, Folder 216)
      - Jones, Margaret W., 1862 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 216)
      - Livingston, Mary, d. 1885, 1862 [] 29 (Box 5, Folder 217)
      - Marvin, Mrs. Elihu (1791-1878)
        See: box 5, folder 214
      - Marvin, Mrs. Selden
        See: box 5, folder 208
      - Mahon, Joseph, 1862 November 6 (Box 5, Folder 218)
      - Marvin, Selden, 1819-1896, 1862 August 26 (Box 5, Folder 218)
      - Micheles [?], Rev. T H, 1862 September 25, undated (Box 5, Folder 218)
      - Newell, W A, 1863 January 27 (Box 5, Folder 219)
      - Nott, Rev. Elephalet, 1861 March 13 (Box 5, Folder 219)
      - Olmsted, Aaron Barlow(*), b. 1812, 1858 May 17-1865 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 220)
      - Olmsted, Almira, b. 1807, 1860 July 23, 1861 November 12, December 20, 1862 September 23, 1865 November 11, November 18 (Box 6, Folder 221)
      - Olmsted, Hannah, b. 1834
        See: box 6, folder 225
      - Olmsted, Rev. James Munson, 1794-1870, 1856 January 16 (Box 6, Folder 222)
      - Olmsted, [Joel Barlow, b. 1817], 1861 November 21, 1862 October 4 (Box 6, Folder 223)
      - Olmsted, Rev. John Wesley(*), 1816-1891, 1860 October 19-1862 October 21 (Box 6, Folder 224)
      - Olmsted, Mrs. John Wesley
        See: box 5, folder 217
      - Olmsted, Julia A., b. 1816
      - Olmsted, L[ois?] S. (1814-1860), Olmsted, J[ulia] A. (b. 1816)?], and Olmsted, H[annah (b. 1834)?], 1849 September 30 (Box 6, Folder 225)
      - Olmsted, Lucy Starr, b. 1816, 1860 August 29 (Box 6, Folder 226)
      - Olmsted, Montgomery, 1842-1875, 1862 September 28 October 15 (Box 6, Folder 227)
      - Olmsted, Sarah Lucy(*), 1840-1871, [1860] January 16-1860 December 26, 1861 January 8-1861 December 25, 1862 January 4-1862 March 29, 1862 April 5-1862 July 28, 1862 August 18-1862 December 19, 1863 January 3-1863 May 23 (Box 6, Folder 228-233)
      - Olmsted, Sarah Lucy, 1840-1871, 1865 September 12, November 1, November 6, December 26, December 29, undated (Box 6, Folder 234)
      - Olmsted, [Zalmon] Sanford, 1820-1891, [1865 December 30] (Box 6, Folder 235)
      - Perley, Samuel, 1861 January 2, February 15, March 7, March 14, April 3, April 13 (Box 6, Folder 236)
      - Perley, S Todd, 1861 January 18, April 8 (Box 6, Folder 237)
      - Prud'homme, E M, 1860 November 30 (Box 6, Folder 237)
      - Read, Rev. James F., 1862 November 29 (Box 6, Folder 238)
      - Ricker, Lizzie M., 1862 August 28, September 21, October 27 (Box 6, Folder 238)
      - Robertsen, Dr. James, 1862 October 14, October 16, November 22, December (Box 6, Folder 238)
      - Safford (Messrs. F.H. and deF.) & Co., 1860 December 14 (Box 6, Folder 239)
      - Samson, George Whitefield, b. 1819, 1862 October 24 (Box 6, Folder 239)
      - Sanford, G[iles, b. 1783?], 1861 December 2 (Box 6, Folder 239)
      - Sawyer, W B, 1861 December 25 (Box 6, Folder 240)
      - Seward, William H[enry], 1801-1872, 1867 February 22, November 6 (Box 6, Folder 241)
      - Shepherd, John L, 1862 July 21 (Box 6, Folder 242)
      - Sibley, John Langdon, 1804-1885, 1860 December 29 (Box 6, Folder 242)
      - Smith, H F, 1856 January (Box 6, Folder 242)
      - Steward, Dr. J. L
        See: box 6, folder 242
      - Taylor, Capt. C E, 1862 August 30 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - Thompson, Mary A, 1862 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - Thorne, Robert T, 1865 November 6 (Box 6, Folder 243)
      - [Turner?], John B., 1862 October 9 (Box 6, Folder 244)
      - Vosburgh, A J, 1862 March 10, 1863 January 3 (Box 6, Folder 245)
      - Wallingford, A M, 1862 April 18 (Box 6, Folder 246)
      - Walworth, Reuben H[yde?], 1789-1867, 1856 July 27 (Box 6, Folder 246)
      - Webb, Rev. Joseph B., 1862 December 21 (Box 6, Folder 246)
      - Wilson, Sen. W, 1862 October 19 (Box 6, Folder 247)
        See also: box 6, folder 224
      - Wolfe, Edgar T., undated (Box 6, Folder 247)
      - Unidentified, 1858 May 21, September 17, September 27, 1860 October 8, 1861 December 8, 1862 January 15 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - Outgoing
      - Barlow, Rebecca, 1788-1861, 1859 April 13 (Box 6, Folder 249)
      - Erie Academy, Trustees of, 1860 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 250)
      - Hansen, Rev. Isaiah L., 1862 December 1 (Box 6, Folder 251)
      - Lyon, Rev. George A., 1858 September 22 (Box 6, Folder 252)
      - Nott, Rev. Eliphalet, 1861 February 28 (Box 6, Folder 253)
      - Olmsted, Mrs. Zalmon (1783-1853)
        See: box 6, folder 249
  - Third-Party Correspondence
    - Allen, H P
      - ALS to Rev. Eliphalet Nott, 1861 March 2 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Cary, L
      - Electrostatic copy of letter to Phoebe Cary, 1824-1871. Original ALS enclosed in Phoebe Cary to L. G. Olmsted, post-1856 Aug 22, Box 5, folder 205, 1856 August 22 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Dayton, Edwin A.
      - ALS to _______, 1862 September 19 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - Dickson, Anne
      - ALS to Dr. [James?] Robertsen, [1862] September 24 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - Ely, Abner L[ord?], 1805-1871
      - ALS to W J S Hull, 1865 December 5 (Box 6, Folder 257)
    - Saunders, F[rederic?], b. 1807
      - ALS to _______; Buckingham, "Asst. Ed. of 'World'.", 1861 January 10 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    - Unidentified, 1860 November 17, 1861 February 26 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Dwight, Timothy, b. 1811
      - ALS to Aaron Barlow Olmsted, b. 1812, 1865 November 28 (Box 6, Folder 260)
    - Ely, Abigail Deborah, 1813-1879
      - ALS to Sarah Lucy Olmsted [Mrs. Matthew (1833-1919) Griswold], 1840-1870, undated (Box 6, Folder 261)
      - Ely, Abigail G(regory)
      - Ely, Mrs. Abner Lord
      - Gregory, Abigail E(ly)
      - Gregory, Mrs. Henry M.
      - Griswold, Mrs. Matthew (1833-1919)
        See: box 6, folder 263
    - Olmsted, Rev. John Wesley, 1816-1891
      - 2 ALS to Aaron Barlow Olmsted, b. 1812, 1861 February 28, March 12 (Box 6, Folder 262)
      - Olmsted, Sarah Lucy, 1840-1870
        - 2 ALS to Elihu Marvin (1791-1878) and Anna Humphreys [Mrs. Elihu Marvin], 1781-1875, 1860 July 27, 1863 April 9 (Box 6, Folder 263)
    - Olmsted, Susan, b. 1837
      - ALS to _______, 1862 September 24 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Journals
    - Olmsted, Lemuel G., 1808-1880
      - "Heterogenious Journal From June 16th up to Oct 22d 1830 During which time I have traveled about two thousand miles giving a Geological account of the country &c. &c. Vol. II MVIIIXXX", [1830 June 16-October 22] (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Financial
    - Receipts, 1859-1865, undated (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Miscellany
    - Notes, medical certificates, tickets, business cards, advertisements, etc., 1861-1862, undated (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - Printed notices, catalogues, and clippings, 1862, undated (Box 7, Folder 268)
  - Diplomas
    - Union College (Schenectady, N.Y.)
      - Diploma for the degree of Bachelor of Arts conferred on Lemuel Gregory Olmsted. Signed by Eliphalet Nott, President, 1834 August 10 (Box 4a)
    - Hanover College (Indiana)
      - Diploma for the degree of Doctor of Laws conferred on Lemuel Gregory Olmsted. Signed by James Wood, President, 1865 (Box 4a)
  - Photographs
    - Olmsted, Sarah Lucy [Mrs. Matthew (1833-1919) Griswold], 1840-1870
      - Photograph album of family, friends and acquaintance. [Photographs of family members include: Timothy Dwight, b. 1811; Eliza Ely,; Seth Ely, 1764-1847; Charles Humphreys, 1861; Rev. James M[unson?] Olmsted, 1794-1870; Lemuel G. Olmsted, 1808-1880; and George Selden, d. 1857.], [c. 1860-1863] (Box 4a, Folder 269)
  - Genealogy
    - Genealogical notes re Olmsted and related families, [Temp. 17th-19th cent.] (Box 4a, Folder 270)
- MISCELLANEOUS, 1762-1856, undated; Series V; 4" (4/5 box)
  Series V is composed of five small, unrelated groups of papers dating from the Revolutionary War era through the first half of the nineteenth century. The first two sections consist of individual items: a draft of a poem by Joel Barlow, and an autobiographical narrative probably written by Christopher Cary (1763-1837). The third and largest section, Dwight Family Manuscripts, contains both family correspondence and two journals kept by Timothy Dwight (1752-1817) of travels through New England. The correspondence treats of such varied subjects as politics in Hartford, Connecticut (Box 7, folder 277), the New York City almshouse (folder 282), an unusual change in skin color of an Afro-American (folder 279), and the last wishes of Timothy Dwight given during a conversation with Theodore Dwight (1764-1846).
  The fourth section of Series V contains eighteen letters to and from John Trumbull (1750-1831) and a sketch of the life of Governor Jonathan Trumbull written by John Trumbull. Included are letters to John Adams and from Aaron Burr discussing politics, and correspondence with other friends and acquaintances concerning politics, Yale College, and various scholarly matters. Since other correspondence of Trumbull is located in Series I and II of this collection, an author index to all of the Trumbull material has been appended to this register.
  The final section of Series V consists of miscellaneous autograph letters and documents signed by such people as John and John Quincy Adams, Henry Clay, and George Washington. Several of the letters are copies or facsimiles; these are marked as such in the folder list which follows.
  - Joel Barlow MSS
    - Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812
      - Draft of "Ode on the Discoveries of Captain Lewis", undated (Box 7, Folder 271)
  - Cary Family MSS
    - [Cary, Christopher, 1763-1837?]
      - Narrative of Early Life and Revolutionary Experiences.[Incomplete?] Originally enclosed in Phoebe Cary, 1824-1871, to Lemuel G. Olmsted post-1856 Aug 22, Box 5, folder 205, undated (Box 7, Folder 272)
  - Dwight Family MSS
    - Correspondence
      - Barnes, Rev. Albert
        - ALS to Eleazar T. Fitch (1791-1871), Serano E. Dwight (1786-1850), and Cleveland J. [Salter?], 1829 September 25 (Box 7, Folder 273)
      - Belknap, Rev. Jeremy, 1744-1798
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1797 November 2 (Box 7, Folder 274)
      - Chauncey, N[athaniel?], 1789-1865
        - ALS to Henry E[dwin?] Dwight, 1797-1832, 1828 March 12 (Box 7, Folder 275)
      - Dwight, Rev. Nathaniel, 1770-1831
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1794 November 8 (Box 7, Folder 276)
      - Dwight, T[heodore], 1764-1846
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1794 November 15 (Box 7, Folder 277)
      - Dwight, Major T[imothy], 1726-1777
        - 2 ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1769 January 30, 1771 July 23 (Box 7, Folder 278)
        - Dwight, Mrs. Timothy (1726-1777)
          See: box 7, folder 281
      - Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817
        - AL to Josiah Meigs, 1799 June 24 (Box 7, Folder 279)
      - Dwight, W[illiam] T[heodore], 1795-1865
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1778-1844, 1835 January 20 (Box 7, Folder 280)
      - Edwards, Mary, 1734-1807
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1785 January 25 (Box 7, Folder 281)
      - Ely, J[ospeh?] M[erriman, b. 1788?]